<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>BLOG_NAME</title>
 <link href="YOUR_URL/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="YOUR_URL"/>
 <updated>2014-03-09T22:53:42-07:00</updated>
 <id>BLOG_URL</id>
 <author>
   <name>BLOG_NAME</name>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Needfinding</title>
   <link href="YOUR_URL/2014/03/09/needfinding.html"/>
   <updated>2014-03-09T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>BLOG_URL/2014/03/09/needfinding</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;takeaway_points&quot;&gt;Takeaway Points:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People in different companies and groups use different communication channels → important that we list / link to / enable as many communication links as possible.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;People need to find experts in their organization very often, other than people with standalone projects (e.g. sales in a specific locale)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Institutional memory of ‘who-to-ask’ lies with senior members of the team, and is passed down from people to people.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;A lot of organizations change quite often, so our app has to be flexible with changes of expertise / directly-responsible individuals.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Subject Matter Experts are chased down by many people, so whenever possible load-balancing recommendations is a good idea.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Might want to consider gamification / incentive for people to answer.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;We cannot rely on user input for knowing expertise, so the more automated we can make this process to be, the better.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;This app needs to integrate with whatever the user already uses at their company to be useful. It’s a high frictional cost to have to open up and learn another tool. Ideally we can seamlessly integrate with existing intranet tools.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See the &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/1M7-DTy38SMOJy9E5T1GbXzaAfWaXCcPY5UeHxB4dogk/viewform&quot;&gt;list of interview transcriptions&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1kPZNwS4oSI3mnM-AV9FD32BVga4PMB_8cwMTitfZ__0/edit&quot;&gt;the notes from the conference call with Chris Iannuccilli (Global Head of Strategy and Operations at Google)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;objective&quot;&gt;Objective:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Validate that there is a need of an application that makes finding subject matter expert in the workplace easier.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Validate that there is a need on a management level for an application that maps out the distribution of knowledge on the workplace.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Find out the demographics of people (which department, what size of company) who often face the problem of finding the right person to ask in the workplace.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Find out the current workflow of finding people to ask on the workplace and the pain points of such workflow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;questions_asked&quot;&gt;Questions asked:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How often do you interact with employees outside your team / office?&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;How do you usually ask questions at work?&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;How do you find people to ask at the workplace?&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;What is the pain points on this process and how can it be improved?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;interview_targets&quot;&gt;Interview targets&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;15 employees or managers at companies of varying sizes and types:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Companies: Google, Intel, Oracle, OptumRx, PIMCO (investment firm), Cargill, ESRI, Alliance Human Services, Raytheon, school district, etc.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Company Type: Software, Medical, Investment Firm, Agriculture, Education, Hardware, Health / Social, Defense Contractor&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Company size: small, medium, national, multinational&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Department: People Operations / HR, Technical Staff, IT, Aerospace Engineer, Software Engineer, Medical Officer, Associate, VP, Teacher, Sales, Department Head, Project Lead&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;results&quot;&gt;Results&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how_often_do_you_interact_with_people_outside_your_team__office&quot;&gt;How often do you interact with people outside your team / office?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Everyday / all the time”
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People Operations&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;IT / Technical Staff&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Software Engineer (working on a project w/ many dependencies),&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Health / social service in management role&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Aerospace Engineer&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Medical officer in management role&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;“Rarely / only to specific set of people”
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hardware Engineer with a relatively standalone responsibility&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Sales only responsible for a specific region&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how_often_do_you_have_questions_at_work&quot;&gt;How often do you have questions at work?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most respondents agrees: “Every day / very often”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how_do_you_usually_ask_questions&quot;&gt;How do you usually ask questions?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In person&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Email&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Video conference&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Phone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how_do_you_find_the_right_person_to_ask&quot;&gt;How do you find the right person to ask?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A lot of them say a variation of:&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;“After a while, you sort of know who you need to talk to - a mental map of: if I need to ask question about X, go to A. If the question is about Y, go to B. etc”&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Ask teammates / senior coworkers / managers if you don’t know.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;“Start with senior people and work downwards”&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;“Start with secretary or principal”&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;This information is passed down from people to people&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Lookup on internal team page or internal directory of ‘who’s in department X?’&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Reference sheet distributed by different teams&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Google has corporate G+ and Google Groups, but most people don’t end up using them.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Google has a “who knows what tool”, that finds where people went to school, what projects they worked on, Google resume, personal interests and their inputted expertise&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Not really used at Google&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;pain_points_on_this_process&quot;&gt;Pain points on this process&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Subject Matter Experts are important people, so they are chased by many people - questions often times get ignored or get short responses.”&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Teams operate differently, so documentations are not standardized (big company is hard to standardize)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;People move around a lot so it’s hard to keep data from being stale.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;“Hard to know who does what in my large company.”&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;It’s rare to get to the right person on first try - often times I get ping-ponged between people until actually getting to the right person&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Hard to know the right person on the team who I should contact - is it the manager? The senior person?&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;“Different offices often have very different software/hardware/communication devices, for example, we have video conferencing and voice capabilities through MS Lync that work extremely well and are cheap, although some offices don’t have headsets or cameras, so we use an actual phone call which costs significantly more.”&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;“Difficult to reach out to those you don’t know, as it nearly always requires a formal email to introduce yourself, etc. and I never know if I’m talking to the right person so I may be just bothering them for information they don’t know anyway.”&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;“Social workers outside the agency often times don’t know about processes and multitask with their cases. It can be time consuming to wait for people to provide the right services / answers.”&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;For questions with technical depth, it’s hard to scope down the project to a short question to other people - it’s hard to pick and choose what details to share.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how_could_that_process_be_improved&quot;&gt;How could that process be improved?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Standardized procedure / central reference in making things more transparent - who is responsible for this project, etc.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The biggest problem is ‘how-to-make-them-answer’.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;With a good tool to search information easily, something like Google Enterprise Search.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;“If I knew the correct subject matter expert (SME) to go to the first time, that would be most beneficial in saving time and getting to the right source. It would be nice to have some type of directory that showed functions and expertise–all that is shared now is the reporting hierarchy.”&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Having a broader net to cast, so I could reach someone whom I may have never spoken to prior. Maybe if there was some way to ask my question, and have everyone see it so they can point me in the right way, would be a better way to drive this, kind of like stack overflow and yahoo answers. A lot of times you don’t know what you don’t know, and so might be looking for the wrong person. It’s better to have a lot of eyes see your problem.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Pink Bagel</title>
   <link href="YOUR_URL/2014/03/05/pink-bagel.html"/>
   <updated>2014-03-05T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>BLOG_URL/2014/03/05/pink-bagel</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In this task we will use advertising to get quick feedback from our potential user about the questions that we are curious about. We started with listing out what we want to know. The questions we came up with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Demographics: who are the most likely to be interested in Dewey the Expertise Mapper?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Types of company
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Technology&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Law&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Retail&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Department
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Engineering&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;HR&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Law&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Sales&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Marketing&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;IT&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Size of company
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;less than 100&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;100 - 1000&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;more than 10000&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Types of employees
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experienced&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;New hire / new grads&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Management&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Product: Tagline&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dewey maps employees’ expertise in your company&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Dewey captures what your employees are capable of&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Dewey captures the distribution of knowledge inside your company&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Dewey - How to find who knows what&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which part of the UI will people be more interested in?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The visualization part&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The text-based UI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Would rendering pictures be significantly better than not?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;linkedin_ads&quot;&gt;LinkedIn Ads&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LinkedIn Ads is our first stab on this task, because of the professional nature of our product. LinkedIn seems to be a good way to slice by demographics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The result: 9,596 impressions 1 click 19.19 USD&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Demographics: US-based Human Resources Employees&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learning: the market size is relatively specific and small, relevant demographic studies will need much more money&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of the very low click through rate, we decided to continue with Facebook instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;facebook_ads&quot;&gt;Facebook Ads&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The focus of this ad is to test whether faces on the graphs make a difference in click-through rate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With 80 USD, the combined result: 80 USD 47 Website Clicks, 63 Clicks $1.61 / website click 13,865 campaign reach 0.378% CTR&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Demographics: Employees of 25 Selected Companies, such as Dell, Cisco, Amazon, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We tested two variations of this ad - one with photos and one without photos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Variation 1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/ads_without_photo.png&quot; alt=&quot;Variation 1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Result:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;22 Website Click, 28 Clicks&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;$1.45 / Website Click&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;5592 Reach&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;0.509% CTR&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Variation 2&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/ads_with_photo.png&quot; alt=&quot;Variation 1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Result:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;26 Website Click, 35 Clicks&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;$1.67 / Website Click&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;6798 Reach&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;0.517%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Benchmarking Product Area</title>
   <link href="YOUR_URL/2014/02/22/benchmarking.html"/>
   <updated>2014-02-22T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>BLOG_URL/2014/02/22/benchmarking</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Enterprise product is a new area for most of us and none of us have previously used Socialcast before. Because of that, we started the benchmarking with the general area of enterprise social network. The full benchmarking document can be seen &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1uXgTH6dltvE6ecdf8HDoV9y4bhoV6A2Md1Djty_wFeg/edit&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, and a comparison matrix can be seen &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheet/ccc?key=0AgxIKrJjqiXwdFVBT25JNk5mRkpDbTdDUmlaZjlLdGc&amp;usp=drive_web#gid=0&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the competitors are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quad from Cisco Systems&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Connections from IBM&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Engage from Jive Software&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;SharePoint Workspace from Microsoft&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Salesforce Chatter from Salesforce&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;StreamWork from SAP&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Yammer from Microsoft&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feature sets of most of these products are similar to real-life social networks (Facebook, Twitter, etc), adapted to workplace environment. For example, there are supports for files and teams. In the coming years, there will be more and more customization of these processes to enterprise settings. A PwC paper suggests that the next generation of corporate social network will be focused on semantic analysis to make sense of the plethora of data floating around in the workplace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also did a benchmarking on Q &amp;amp; A products, such as Quora, Jelly, Ask.com, and ChaCha. We like the people suggestions on Quora in connecting people to experts and the smart push notification system of Jelly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After &lt;a href=&quot;/internal/2014/02/17/pivoting.html&quot;&gt;pivoting&lt;/a&gt;, we looked at expertise mapper / expertise finder that exists on the market. See the full benchmarking document &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1gZTdLcREtbPWPnqGhci8yzLniOswV3B5lqP-OmzhafA/edit?usp=drive_web&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Key Takings&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The problem ‘find the best person in topic X’ or ‘find the best person to answer question Y’ has been tackled in numerous different ways, catered to different use cases&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Most services here are painful to use and very text-heavy, with lists of never-ending topics to choose from. Approaching this problem visually will differentiate our product.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Services that attempt automatic mapping restrict the scope to certain types of sources or certain verticals.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;A learning mechanism for the people suggestions (either via likes or votes) is crucial.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Pivoting</title>
   <link href="YOUR_URL/2014/02/17/pivoting.html"/>
   <updated>2014-02-17T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>BLOG_URL/2014/02/17/pivoting</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On Dewey’s short group meeting with Jay on 11/2, Jay brought up some concerns about our product specification. At this point, we were set on doing the original product that VMWare suggested: a bot that replies on conversations on Socialcast with relevant data and people who might be able to answer the question. The concerns with this idea are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This project is almost entirely backend-focused with no UI element, which:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;do not utilize the full skill sets of our team members&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;will be difficult to split up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Our level of excitement on the product is questionable, because it feels like a project that VMWare ‘tasked’ on us instead of something we came up on our own.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Agreeing with these two observations, we went back to the drawing board and restarted our brainstorming session. On the meeting today (Wed Feb 12), we talked about a couple of different ideas:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kinect-related projects
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;teach fine motor skills - example: cooking, shoot a basketball&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;identify moods from faces&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;virtual classroom; as a teaching aid&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Data visualization about employee’s expertise
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;if you had a visualization of topics relevant to your company, and you could “drill down” and find people relevant to the topic, and maybe also see why they’re listed as relevant (expertise, email thread, etc)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;“making it easier for people to know who to ask inside the company about a certain topic”&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;use case: new hire wants to know how search infrastructure works. New hire doesn’t know who to contact, so they go to Dewey to discover who to ask about it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The difficulties of onboarding
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are always the same questions that a new hire has&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Poor documentation for how to use internal tools, such as issue tracking&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Need to know who to ask certain questions (“Oh, just ask John about that, he dealt with that last week”)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Capturing information &amp;amp; capturing people relevant to onboarding&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Recommend people to ask about certain questions, similar to Dewey&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Collecting information about where employee’s time is spent
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;track how much time is spent in certain files in a project; maybe could help indicate that a project needs more resources (developers) or that the engineers are spending too much time on something considered not a high priority, could help engineers manage their time more effectively&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Data visualization about interactions between employees
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hierarchical information is already captured, but what about seeing who works with who most often?&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;could uncover interesting conclusions about single points of failure, an employee who is particularly crucial to a team’s success, or just discovering clusters of people who tend to work well together&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Postsecret / geocaching
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;having people share “secrets” tied to a location, can only be viewed if person actually visits location&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;captures transience of secrets&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;a way of anonymously sharing how you feel; interesting method of interpersonal interaction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;there is value in enterprises using social applications
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;enterprise social networks were created to better connect people within a company&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;perhaps content on social apps can be used to express the company’s culture or team; can be used for PR; recruiting; teambuilding&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;for the workplace
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tinder experience&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;timehop&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;game that quizzes you on coworkers&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;meet people in the workplace&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;send picture asking who it is&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Integrated search engine in the workplace
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;information overload in the workplace, people don’t know where things are&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first idea that gets traction from all of us is #9. However, we found out about Google Enterprise Search that does exactly what we want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the next brainstorming session, on Feb 16, we zeroed in on the aspect of the original Dewey Bot project that attracted us in the first place -t the ide aof surfacing appropriate people to a particular problem. Brett was away for a wedding, and his email made this idea seem more and more realistic and exciting: &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/brainstorm_email.png&quot; alt=&quot;Bretts email&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During this meeting we fleshed out more about what this product will feel like, as well as exploring the possible use cases. All of us have experienced woes in finding the right people to ask during our internships, so this makes us even more excited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the next brainstorming meeting, on Feb 17, we came out with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1lmRcVgWUTT7dF6gtfsaLODK6CVB89jlFiGCdW37N9tU/&quot;&gt;Product Specification for Dewey&lt;/a&gt;. We officially pivot our product to be a webapp where employees inside a company can easily create, edit and explore expertise graph within a company.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Introducing Dewey</title>
   <link href="YOUR_URL/2014/01/24/naming-dewey.html"/>
   <updated>2014-01-24T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>BLOG_URL/2014/01/24/naming-dewey</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;After a bunch of brainstorming on names, we finally come up with a name that everyone likes: Dewey!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We decided pretty quickly that we want a person name that represents knowledge - either the collection, the processing, or the organization of knowledge. This is, at its core, the crux of the project that VMWare brought forward to us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We brainstormed a couple of names, such as Athena, Minerva, Prometheus, Sheldon, Sherlock. Sherlock and Dewey were our final two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The name Dewey comes from The Dewey Decimal Classification (DDC), or Dewey Decimal System, is a proprietary library classification system first published in the United States by Melvil Dewey in 1876. This classification system, used in 200,000 libraries in at least 135 countries, is hugely valuable in organizing the vast knowledge held by the libraries. DDC’s goal is quite similar to our own. In large enterprises, knowledge are interspersed in so many places that it is extremely difficult for people to manage and find. We hope that our system, like DDC, can help organize and make sense of this complexity, hence bringing productivity and effective knowledge sharing in the workplace.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>About Socialcast</title>
   <link href="YOUR_URL/2014/01/23/about-socialcast.html"/>
   <updated>2014-01-23T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>BLOG_URL/2014/01/23/about-socialcast</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Socialcast is an enterprise social platform that connects people to the knowledge, ideas and resources they need to work better together. Socialcast is owned by VMWare, and used by more than 20,000 companies around the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fundamental value of Socialcast is merging many different systems used in business settings, reducing the need to switch between systems to do work. Many companies use different services to do different things, such as uploading files, gauging employee interests / ideas, etc. Each functions in the company often use different tools to do their work. Through its API, Reach Extensions and its vast functionalities, Socialcast serves as a central hub that integrate all these systems. Examples of applications that can be integrated using Reach Extensions are Gmail, Salesforce, Sharepoint, and JIRA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Socialcast’s functionalities:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Project Management&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Share ideas&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Including external Streams (e.g. Twitter)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Private messages&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Questions and answers&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Socialcast Thanks&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Create challenges to brainstorm ideas&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Internationalization&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Analytics&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;API&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Mobile apps (iOS, Android, Blackberry)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Embeddable conversations to different apps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Socialcast’s REST API (http://developers.socialcast.com/) provides programmatic access to the same functionality that is available via the community’s Socialcast website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Example usage of Socialcast’s API:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Philips “We used Socialcast’s API to connect with Connect Us, our enterprise social platform. We created a private group for leaders to engage and have dialogues. Upon opening the summit app, the saw the activity stream on which they could create their own messages and engage with other messages. This made it easy for them to connect with other participants and share information, photos and videos. All content on Philips’ Socialcast community was projected onto meeting walls, creating a powerful, visual experience.” http://www.simply-communicate.com/case-studies/company-profile/philips%E2%80%99-leadership-summit-goes-all-digital&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Humana “Using the Socialcast API, a team of Human Resources employees conceptualized and developed a suite of apps and game-like activities with the goal of strengthening the community. Humana’s goal was to make Socialcast – or “Buzz,” as it’s called internally, into an engaging and helpful tool for employees. The team created “The Hive,” a personal social graph for every employee that highlighted one’s participation level and the fellow Buzzers with whom they collaborated the most. They also created apps to highlight unanswered questions, participation heat maps, and trending conversations.” http://www.readwriteweb.com/enterprise/2011/12/how-humana-used-the-socialcast.php&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Team Formation</title>
   <link href="YOUR_URL/2014/01/21/team-formation.html"/>
   <updated>2014-01-21T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>BLOG_URL/2014/01/21/team-formation</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Dewey Team was formed on Jan 21, 2014 at CS 210 Large Group Meeting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Members of the team arrive at this project in different ways: Brett and Stephen just got into CS 210 class just hours or days earlier. John, Will and Veni ranked this project highly for different reasons - John for the NLP focus, Veni for the automated Q&amp;amp;A element of it, and Will for the possibility of improving social connections in the workplace. Either way, we are all excited to be working with VMWare in these two quarters!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right out of the gate, we have to brainstorm things like name, logo, and project idea, as well as developing relationship with our liaisons from VMWare. The most important thing about these early days, however, is perhaps getting to know each other better and setting a good base of our working relationship in the next two quarters.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>